DAVIDE GHIOTTO

September, 2020

Montecchio Maggiore (VI) Italy | +39 345 577 98 38 | dghiotto.careers@gmail.com | linkedin: davide-ghiotto

CURRICULUM VITAE

CARRIER PROFILE

Junior Full Stack Developer with 1 year of experience implementing custom Angular Web Applications and core Java microservices, for large scale use in the banking sector. Developed reusable components and effective models to keep the pace with continuous delivery of high quality products.

Core competences include: Angular Framework, Java 8, Node.js, web API, TypeScript, JavaScript, SQL, Oracle Database, Spring, Git, HTML, CSS, Sass.

EXPERIENCE

Reply S.p.A - Cluster Financial Services

Nov 2019 to present

Full Stack Developer

Developed complete Angular Web Applications, integrated with backend Java API, in a microservice oriented architecture, in order to build a large scale platform capable of handling the complexity of financial services world. Implemented high quality code to speed up further developments and lower maintenance work in a continuous delivery environment.

- Created a generalized conceptual model to efficiently handle user interactions and data flow leading to an uniformed solution capable of avoid potential error situations and repetitive work
- Implemented a decentralized error handling strategy to avoid single point of failure with an increased reliability of the system
- Improved data retrieval time through careful analysis and optimization of database's requests along with asynchronous client-side code

Zucchetti S.p.A May 2019 to July 2019

Nodejs Developer

Stage

Developed a Nodejs application that grouped together different machine learning methods under a common interface. Presented the visual results of the algorithms on a web page transpiling the server side code into ES6 modules with Webpack.

- Created a common graphical interface to interact uniformly with different machine learning methods
- Implemented state-of-the-art training algorithm for Support Vector Machines to achieve better performance thanks to a deep mathematical analysis

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Web technologies: Angular, TypeScript, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Sass
- Backend technologies: Nodejs, Java, Python, Spring
- Database: MySQL, POSTGRES, ORACLE
- Statistics: R, Python, Pandas
- Versioning: Git, Github, Bitbucket

EDUCATION

Master's Degree Data Science

29.6/30 weighted average

University of Study of Padua

2019 to present

Bachelor's Degree Computer Science Uni

University of Study of Padua 2016-2019

110L/110
Highschool Graduation

Liceo Scientifico Statale G.B. Quadri 2011-2016

87/100 CERTIFICATES

• **B2** First, 2015

OTHER SKILLS

Languages English: professional proficiency. Italian: native.